Chapter 129. The cabin.
Ahab moving to go on deck. Pip catches him by the hand to follow.
Lad. Lad, I tell thee, thou must not follow Ahab now. The hour is coming when
Ahab would not scare thee from him, yet would not have thee by him. There is
that in thee, poor lad, which I feel too curing to my malady. Like cures like,
and for this hunt my malady becomes my most desired health. Do thou abide below
here, where they shall serve thee as if thou w the captain. I, lad, thou shalt
sit here in my own screwed chair.
Another screw to it thou must be. No, no, no. Ye have not a whole body, sir.
Do you but use poor me for your one lost
leg? Only tread upon me, sir. I ask no more, so I remain a part of ye.
Oh, spite of million villains, this makes me a bigot in the fadeless
fidelity of man, and a black and crazy.
But me thinks like cures like applies to him, too. He grows so sane again.
They tell me, sir, that Stub did once desert poor little Pip, whose drowned
bones now show white for all the blackness of his living skin. But I will
never desert ye, sir, as Stub did him.
Sir, I must go with ye. If thou speakest thus to me much more. Ahab's purpose
keels up in him, I tell thee no, it cannot be. Oh, good master, master,
master, weep so, and I will murder thee.
Have a care, for Ahab too is mad.
Listen, and thou wilt often hear my ivory foot upon the deck, and still know
that I am there. And now I quit thee.
Thy hand met.
True art thou, lad, as the circumference to its center. So God forever bless
thee. And if it come to that, God forever save thee. Let what will befall.
Ahab goes. Pip steps one step forward.
Here he this instance stood. I stand in his air, but I'm alone.
Now we're even. Poor Pip here. I could endure it, but he is missing. Pip. Pip.
Ding-dong ding. Who's seen Pip? He must be up here. Let's try the door. What?
Neither lock nor bolt nor bar. And yet there's no opening it. It must be the
spell. He told me to stay here. I And told me this screwed chair was mine.
Here then, I'll seat me against the transom in the ship's full middle. All
her keel and her three mass before me.
Here our old sailors say in their black 74s, great admirals sometimes sit at
table and lorded over rows of captains and lieutenants. Huh? What's this?
Epolettes. Epilelettes. The epilelettes all come crowding. Pass round the
decanters. Glad to see you. Fill up.
Msur. What an odd feeling now when a black boy's host to white men with gold
lace upon their coats. Msures. Have you seen one pip? A little negro lad 5 ft
high hang dog look and cowardly jumped from a whaleboat once. Seen him? No.
Well then, fill up again, captains, and let's drink shame upon all cowards. I
name no names. Shame upon them. put one foot upon the table. Shame upon all
cowards, hissed above there. I hear ivory.
Oh, master. Master, I am indeed downhearted when you walk
over me. But here I'll stay, though this stern strikes rocks and they bulge
through and oysters come to join me.